<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Good Hacker</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Good Hacker</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 18:27:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thegoodhacker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PHP GIT server hacked and backdoor injected in PHP source code</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/php-git-server-hacked-and-backdoor-inserted-in-php-source-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 09:47:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/php-git-server-hacked-and-backdoor-inserted-in-php-source-code/</guid><description>On 28 of March, two malicious commits have been pushed to the PHP official git repository. PHP is maintaining its own git infrastructure under the domain git.php.net.
The attacker has signed the commit as if its made by the creator of PHP Rasmus Ledrof and Nikita Popov one of the well-known PHP maintainers.
The issue was reported by Nikita https://news-web.php.net/php.internals/113838
The Backdoor The first commit which is forged to be signed off by Ledrof is modifying the ext/zlib/zlib.</description></item><item><title>ReDos explained - The ugly face of regular expression - Arabic</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/videos/redos-explained-the-ugly-face-of-regular-expression-arabic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 09:47:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/videos/redos-explained-the-ugly-face-of-regular-expression-arabic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The unsecure node vm module</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/the-unsecure-node-vm-module/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 09:47:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/the-unsecure-node-vm-module/</guid><description>As any nodejs developer you should often check the nodejs documentation look for new modules or new features or even a change in the current API. If you do you will notice a module called &amp;ldquo;VM&amp;rdquo; (Executing Javascript). This is a very interesting module as per nodejs documentation defination &amp;ldquo;The vm module enables compiling and running code within V8 Virtual Machine contexts&amp;rdquo;
Although the documentation state that &amp;ldquo;The vm module is not a security mechanism.</description></item><item><title>SSRF vulnerability in Uppy, Detected by Shieldfy</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/uppy-ssrf-vulnerability-detected-by-shieldfy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 09:47:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/uppy-ssrf-vulnerability-detected-by-shieldfy/</guid><description>In this post, we will explain how Shieldfy detected an SSRF ( Server-side request forgery ) vulnerability in Uppy, one of the popular packages in NPM, diving into the technical details of the vulnerability, exploitation and the fix.
Uppy is a sleek, modular JavaScript file uploader that integrates seamlessly with any application. It’s fast, easy to use and lets you worry about more important problems than building a file uploader. Uppy has more than 130,000 downloads a month.</description></item><item><title>SQL Injection vulnerability in laravel-query-builder</title><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/sql-injection-laravel-query-builder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 09:47:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/posts/sql-injection-laravel-query-builder/</guid><description>The popular package: Laravel-query-builder has released a new security update fixing a serious SQL Injection.laravel-query-builder allows developers to filter, sort and include eloquent (Laravel ORM) relations based on a request. The QueryBuilder used in this package extends Laravel’s default Eloquent builder.
Attack Risk: Critical / Remote Vulnerability: SQL Injection Vendor: Spatie/laravel-query-builder Language: PHP Patched version: 1.16.1 / 1.17.1 Due to the way Laravel builder parse the string to query, the hacker can leverage this to attack the application with SQL Injection attack See the official advisory here</description></item><item><title/><link>https://thegoodhacker.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thegoodhacker.com/about/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>